### Adham Fouad Hussein

# **Software Engineer**

Phone Number: +201275836012 Email: adham@adhamfouad.cf linkedin.com/in/adham-fouad/

With the same enthusiasm that drove me to code as a 10-year-old, I have developed my skills as a diligent software engineer for over 8 years. I have more than 4 years of professional experience in creating commercial applications and software solutions for various domains and industries. I am eager to join your company and contribute to its innovative and global projects.

# **Experience**

### **Software Development Director**

Nation Builders – The US Embassy in Cairo in collaboration with The Ministry of Youth - September 2022–Present

- Contributing code to more than forty projects.
- Involved in idea generation, business analysis and technical design through development and deployment across a variety of technologies.
- Guide and help developers from USA and Egypt throughout the program.
- · Set up development environments for all teams.
- Debug and test produced code from all joining teams.
- Coach teams about best practices for preventing design flaws that affect reliability, responsiveness, and speed.
- Mentor and coach, the joining developers from all teams to choose the most suitable frameworks and tools to help them.
- Demonstrate best-practice software engineering including aspects of agile methodologies, unit testing, refactoring, code reviews, continuous build, and deployment processes.

#### •

### Software Engineer & Team Leader

Nation Builders – The US Embassy in Cairo in collaboration with The Ministry of Youth - September 2020-November 2021

- Built a cross-platform responsive Education platform named EDUCO.
- Led a team while developing the product, documenting it, making a complete study about it, reviewing, and helping other teams.
- Custom Flutter Widgets
- Changing Open-source Widgets to support unsupported platforms.
- Live/Recorded Video Streaming
- P2P Video & Audio Calls
- Group chats
- Scalable API to run on AWS supporting millions of streams per month.
- Tokenization

# Shift Your Life - All in one productivity and lifestyle app - User Client + Admin Dashboard + API.

- Built and perfected all of this to be as fast and dependable as possible using Flutter and NodeJS
- · Notes, Calendar, Reminder
- Firebase Cloud messaging
- · Muslim prayers alarms
- · Qibla, using GPS.
- Tasks Checklist
- Azkaar

### **Library Management System**

- Built a stable system to process hundreds of transactions every day.
- Efficient search to manage to find what they need from thousands of books.
- Made with C# WinForms, .Net, and Built on MSSQL server.
- Made it efficient enough to run on a dual core machine alongside other programs.

- 80-160MB of RAM while opening all the forms.
- · Telerik Forms

#### Education

#### **High School Diploma, Mathematics**

Manarat El Mostaqbal Language Schools September 2020–August 2023

- Won multiple coding competitions across the years.
- · Led the Coding community club.
- Instructed Coding courses for three different age groups.
- Led the Students' Union

#### Skills

- Software development
- Adaptability
- Teamwork
- Agile frameworks
- Interpersonal communication skills
- C#, C++, Dart, JavaScript, Java, Python 3, PHP, HTML, CSS, SQL Server, No SQL
- Flutter, React, React Native, Qt, WordPress, RAD, Delphi, Bootstrap 3-5, Laravel, React, VueJS, NodeJS, WinForms, WPF, .NET Core, .NET 4-6, Firebase.
- Practical knowledge of SQL and database concepts
- Solid knowledge of cybersecurity principles
- Linux/UNIX (command-line tools, shell scripts, operations).
- · Designed and built complex systems (architecture, design patterns, reliability, and scaling).

# Languages

- Arabic Native
- English Fluent/Native (C1)
- German Intermediate (B2+)